<translations>
<comment></comment>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-432</id>
	<key><![CDATA[[%sworld%s]%s, gameRule, value]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-445</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Yes]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-2878</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Examples]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3788</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Vital Info]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3789</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Find a bug in this page? %sEdit this page yourself, then submit a pull request.%s (Note this page is automatically generated from the documentation in the source code.)]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3791</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Usages]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3792</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sorry, there are no examples for this function! :(]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3813</id>
	<key><![CDATA[None]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5152</id>
	<key><![CDATA[About]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Abøüt]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5153</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Home]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Hømə]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5154</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Privacy Policy]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Prîvåcʎ Pølîcʎ]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5155</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sponsors]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Spønsørs]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5156</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Help]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Həlp]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5157</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Team. All rights reserved.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Təåm. All rîghts rəsərvəd.]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5158</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Docs]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Døcs]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-6104</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOPATROLSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOTRADERSPAWNING, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, FORGIVEDEADPLAYERS, FREEZEDAMAGE, KEEPINVENTORY, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, PLAYERSSLEEPINGPERCENTAGE, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SPAWNRADIUS, SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS, or UNIVERSALANGER.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-6660</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOPATROLSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOTRADERSPAWNING, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, FORGIVEDEADPLAYERS, FREEZEDAMAGE, KEEPINVENTORY, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, PLAYERSSLEEPINGPERCENTAGE, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SPAWNRADIUS, SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS, UNIVERSALANGER, or DOWARDENSPAWNING.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-6731</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, BLOCKEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOPATROLSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOTRADERSPAWNING, DOWARDENSPAWNING, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, FORGIVEDEADPLAYERS, FREEZEDAMAGE, GLOBALSOUNDEVENTS, KEEPINVENTORY, LAVASOURCECONVERSION, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, PLAYERSSLEEPINGPERCENTAGE, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SPAWNRADIUS, SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS, TNTEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, UNIVERSALANGER, or WATERSOURCECONVERSION.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-6739</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, BLOCKEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOPATROLSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOTRADERSPAWNING, DOWARDENSPAWNING, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, FORGIVEDEADPLAYERS, FREEZEDAMAGE, GLOBALSOUNDEVENTS, KEEPINVENTORY, LAVASOURCECONVERSION, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, PLAYERSSLEEPINGPERCENTAGE, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SNOWACCUMULATIONHEIGHT, SPAWNRADIUS, SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS, TNTEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, UNIVERSALANGER, or WATERSOURCECONVERSION.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-6783</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, BLOCKEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, COMMANDMODIFICATIONBLOCKLIMIT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOPATROLSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOTRADERSPAWNING, DOVINESSPREAD, DOWARDENSPAWNING, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, FORGIVEDEADPLAYERS, FREEZEDAMAGE, GLOBALSOUNDEVENTS, KEEPINVENTORY, LAVASOURCECONVERSION, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, PLAYERSSLEEPINGPERCENTAGE, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SNOWACCUMULATIONHEIGHT, SPAWNRADIUS, SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS, TNTEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, UNIVERSALANGER, or WATERSOURCECONVERSION.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-6910</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, BLOCKEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, COMMANDMODIFICATIONBLOCKLIMIT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOPATROLSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOTRADERSPAWNING, DOVINESSPREAD, DOWARDENSPAWNING, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, ENDERPEARLSVANISHONDEATH, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, FORGIVEDEADPLAYERS, FREEZEDAMAGE, GLOBALSOUNDEVENTS, KEEPINVENTORY, LAVASOURCECONVERSION, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, PLAYERSSLEEPINGPERCENTAGE, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SNOWACCUMULATIONHEIGHT, SPAWNRADIUS, SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS, TNTEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, UNIVERSALANGER, or WATERSOURCECONVERSION.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-7065</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, BLOCKEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, COMMANDMODIFICATIONBLOCKLIMIT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOPATROLSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOTRADERSPAWNING, DOVINESSPREAD, DOWARDENSPAWNING, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, ENDERPEARLSVANISHONDEATH, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, FORGIVEDEADPLAYERS, FREEZEDAMAGE, GLOBALSOUNDEVENTS, KEEPINVENTORY, LAVASOURCECONVERSION, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXCOMMANDFORKCOUNT, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, PLAYERSNETHERPORTALCREATIVEDELAY, PLAYERSNETHERPORTALDEFAULTDELAY, PLAYERSSLEEPINGPERCENTAGE, PROJECTILESCANBREAKBLOCKS, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SNOWACCUMULATIONHEIGHT, SPAWNRADIUS, SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS, TNTEXPLOSIONDROPDECAY, UNIVERSALANGER, or WATERSOURCECONVERSION.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-7409</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. The gameRule can be announceAdvancements, blockExplosionDropDecay, commandBlockOutput, commandModificationBlockLimit, disableElytraMovementCheck, disableRaids, doDaylightCycle, doEntityDrops, doFireTick, doImmediateRespawn, doInsomnia, doLimitedCrafting, doMobLoot, doMobSpawning, doPatrolSpawning, doTileDrops, doTraderSpawning, doVinesSpread, doWardenSpawning, doWeatherCycle, drowningDamage, enderPearlsVanishOnDeath, fallDamage, fireDamage, forgiveDeadPlayers, freezeDamage, globalSoundEvents, keepInventory, lavaSourceConversion, logAdminCommands, maxCommandChainLength, maxCommandForkCount, maxEntityCramming, mobExplosionDropDecay, mobGriefing, naturalRegeneration, playersNetherPortalCreativeDelay, playersNetherPortalDefaultDelay, playersSleepingPercentage, projectilesCanBreakBlocks, randomTickSpeed, reducedDebugInfo, sendCommandFeedback, showDeathMessages, snowAccumulationHeight, spawnChunkRadius, spawnRadius, spectatorsGenerateChunks, tntExplosionDropDecay, universalAnger, or waterSourceConversion.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-7535</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful. The gameRule can be announceAdvancements, blockExplosionDropDecay, commandBlockOutput, commandModificationBlockLimit, disableElytraMovementCheck, disablePlayerMovementCheck, disableRaids, doDaylightCycle, doEntityDrops, doFireTick, doImmediateRespawn, doInsomnia, doLimitedCrafting, doMobLoot, doMobSpawning, doPatrolSpawning, doTileDrops, doTraderSpawning, doVinesSpread, doWardenSpawning, doWeatherCycle, drowningDamage, enderPearlsVanishOnDeath, fallDamage, fireDamage, forgiveDeadPlayers, freezeDamage, globalSoundEvents, keepInventory, lavaSourceConversion, logAdminCommands, maxCommandChainLength, maxCommandForkCount, maxEntityCramming, minecartMaxSpeed, mobExplosionDropDecay, mobGriefing, naturalRegeneration, playersNetherPortalCreativeDelay, playersNetherPortalDefaultDelay, playersSleepingPercentage, projectilesCanBreakBlocks, randomTickSpeed, reducedDebugInfo, sendCommandFeedback, showDeathMessages, snowAccumulationHeight, spawnChunkRadius, spawnRadius, spectatorsGenerateChunks, tntExplosionDropDecay, universalAnger, or waterSourceConversion.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-7598</id>
	<key><![CDATA[The gameRule can be announceAdvancements, blockExplosionDropDecay, commandBlockOutput, commandModificationBlockLimit, disableElytraMovementCheck, disablePlayerMovementCheck, disableRaids, doDaylightCycle, doEntityDrops, doFireTick, doImmediateRespawn, doInsomnia, doLimitedCrafting, doMobLoot, doMobSpawning, doPatrolSpawning, doTileDrops, doTraderSpawning, doVinesSpread, doWardenSpawning, doWeatherCycle, drowningDamage, enderPearlsVanishOnDeath, fallDamage, fireDamage, forgiveDeadPlayers, freezeDamage, globalSoundEvents, keepInventory, lavaSourceConversion, logAdminCommands, maxCommandChainLength, maxCommandForkCount, maxEntityCramming, minecartMaxSpeed, mobExplosionDropDecay, mobGriefing, naturalRegeneration, playersNetherPortalCreativeDelay, playersNetherPortalDefaultDelay, playersSleepingPercentage, projectilesCanBreakBlocks, randomTickSpeed, reducedDebugInfo, sendCommandFeedback, showDeathMessages, snowAccumulationHeight, spawnChunkRadius, spawnRadius, spectatorsGenerateChunks, tntExplosionDropDecay, universalAnger, or waterSourceConversion.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-7604</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sets the value of the gamerule for the specified world. If world is not given the value is set for all worlds. Returns true if successful.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
</translations>
