<translations>
<comment></comment>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-445</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Yes]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-920</id>
	<key><![CDATA[mixed]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-1089</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Returns an associative array containing the values of all existing gamerules for the given world. If the gameRule parameter is specified, the function only returns that one value instead of an array. The gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOWEATHERCYCLE, KEEPINVENTORY, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SPAWNRADIUS, SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS, or DISABLERAIDS.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-1099</id>
	<key><![CDATA[world, %s[%sgameRule%s]]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-2878</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Examples]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3788</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Vital Info]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3789</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Find a bug in this page? %sEdit this page yourself, then submit a pull request.%s (Note this page is automatically generated from the documentation in the source code.)]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3791</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Usages]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3792</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sorry, there are no examples for this function! :(]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3813</id>
	<key><![CDATA[None]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5152</id>
	<key><![CDATA[About]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Abøüt]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5153</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Home]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Hømə]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5154</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Privacy Policy]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Prîvåcʎ Pølîcʎ]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5155</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sponsors]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5156</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Help]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Həlp]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5157</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Team. All rights reserved.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Təåm. All rîghts rəsərvəd.]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5158</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Docs]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto><![CDATA[Døcs]]></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5318</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Returns an associative array containing the values of all existing gamerules for the given world. If the gameRule parameter is specified, the function only returns that one value instead of an array. The gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, KEEPINVENTORY, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SPAWNRADIUS, or SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-5366</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Returns an associative array containing the values of all existing gamerules for the given world. If the gameRule parameter is specified, the function only returns that one value instead of an array. The gameRule can be ANNOUNCEADVANCEMENTS, COMMANDBLOCKOUTPUT, DISABLEELYTRAMOVEMENTCHECK, DISABLERAIDS, DODAYLIGHTCYCLE, DOENTITYDROPS, DOFIRETICK, DOIMMEDIATERESPAWN, DOINSOMNIA, DOLIMITEDCRAFTING, DOMOBLOOT, DOMOBSPAWNING, DOPATROLSPAWNING, DOTILEDROPS, DOTRADERSPAWNING, DOWEATHERCYCLE, DROWNINGDAMAGE, FALLDAMAGE, FIREDAMAGE, KEEPINVENTORY, LOGADMINCOMMANDS, MAXCOMMANDCHAINLENGTH, MAXENTITYCRAMMING, MOBGRIEFING, NATURALREGENERATION, RANDOMTICKSPEED, REDUCEDDEBUGINFO, SENDCOMMANDFEEDBACK, SHOWDEATHMESSAGES, SPAWNRADIUS, or SPECTATORSGENERATECHUNKS.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
</translations>
