<translations>
<comment></comment>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-445</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Yes]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-741</id>
	<key><![CDATA[F %s yaw, pitch %s player, F %s player, yaw, pitch %s player %s &lt;none&gt;]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-920</id>
	<key><![CDATA[mixed]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-2878</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Examples]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3788</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Vital Info]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3789</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Find a bug in this page? %sEdit this page yourself, then submit a pull request.%s (Note this page is automatically generated from the documentation in the source code.)]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3791</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Usages]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3792</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Sorry, there are no examples for this function! :(]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-3813</id>
	<key><![CDATA[None]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-4555</id>
	<key><![CDATA[Gets or sets the direction the player is facing.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
<translationBlock>
	<id>art-4556</id>
	<key><![CDATA[When using the first variation, expects an integer 0-3, which will set the direction the player faces using their existing pitch (up and down) but sets their yaw (left and right) to one of the cardinal directions, as follows: 0 - West, 1 - South, 2 - East, 3 - North, which corresponds to the directions given by F when viewed with F3. In the second variation, specific yaw and pitches can be provided. If the player is not specified, the current player is used. If just the player is specified, that player's yaw and pitch are returned as an array, or if no arguments are given, the current player's yaw and pitch are returned as an array. The function returns %s when setting the values. (Note that while this function looks like it has ambiguous arguments, players cannot be named numbers.) A note on numbers: The values returned by the getter will always be as such: pitch will always be a number between 90 and -90, with -90 being the player looking up, and 90 being the player looking down. Yaw will always be a number between 0 and 359.9~. When setting the facing, pitch must be a number between -90 and 90, and yaw may be any number. If the number given is not between 0 and 359.9~, it will be normalized first. 0 is dead west, 90 is north, etc.]]></key>
	<comment></comment>
	<translation></translation>
	<auto></auto>
</translationBlock>
</translations>
